Henry A. Grunwald Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Time, inc. Editorial Files, 1941-2005 (Box 98-196)
  - Subject Files, 1949-1987 (Box 149-187)
    - 1979
      - Magazine development (Box 165)
      - Mondale, Walter, meeting, 16-17 Jan. (Box 165)
      - Raein, Parvis (Box 165)
      - Role of editor in chief (Box 165)
      - Strategic Arms Limitation Talks II Symposium, 5 June (Box 165)
      - Science magazine, (3 folders) (Box 165)
      - Staff memoranda (Box 165)
      - Time, inc. Conference on Antitrust, Washington, D.C., 6-8 May, (2 folders) (Box 165)
      - Time magazine "80s" issue (Box 165)
      - Time magazine leadership cover, 6 Aug. (Box 165)
      - Washington Star dinner, 13 Sept., (2 folders) (Box 166)
      - Washington Star editorials (Box 166)
      - World Press Freedom Committee, (2 folders) (Box 166)
    - 1980
      - American Enterprise Institute for Public Policy Research, "A Decade of Study of the Constitution, Second Annual Conference" (Box 166)
      - American Society of Magazine Editors intern lunch, 22 Aug. (Box 166)
      - Business lunch, Los Angeles, Calif., 25 Feb., (2 folders) (Box 166)
      - "China Trying to Face Reality," Washington Star, 16 Nov., (2 folders) (Box 166)
      - Council on Foreign Relations discussion group on United States-West European relations, 29 Jan. (Box 167)
      - Crawford, Clare, and Reuven Frank (Box 167)
      - Fortune Corporate Communications Seminar, Monterey, Calif., 30 Mar.-3 Apr., (2 folders) (Box 167)
      - Fortune departments (Box 167)
      - Fortune fiftieth anniversary, (2 folders) (Box 167)
      - Heiskell, Andrew, retirement dinner, 1 Oct., (2 folders) (Box 167)
      - Henry R. Pringle Memorial Lecture, Columbia University Graduate School of Journalism, New York, N.Y., 12 May (Box 167)
      - J. Walter Thompson Company board of directors meeting, 15 Oct. (Box 167)
      - Jessup, John K. (Box 167)
      - Kissinger, Henry, Friars Club dinner, 3 May (Box 167)
      - Letters to Republican and Democratic delegates (Box 167)
      - Mili, Gjon, International Center of Photography, sixth anniversary gala, 12 Nov. (Box 167)
      - Muskie, Edmund, Foreign Policy Association (Box 167)
      - People in the Eighties: A Look Ahead, Phoenix, Ariz., 30 Mar.-2 Apr. (Box 167)
      - Perlez, Jane (Box 167)
      - Presidential election (Box 167)
      - Reagan, Ronald (Box 167)
      - Staff parties, Mar., (2 folders) (Box 167)
      - Time, inc. Seminar on Soviet-American Relations, New York, N.Y., 5 Mar. (Box 167)
      - Time magazine Boston jubilee dinner, 10 Apr. (Box 168)
      - Time magazine international sales conference, 1 July (Box 168)
      - Time magazine political meeting, Washington, D.C., 13-15 Jan. (Box 168)
      - Time magazine Soviet Union issue, 23 June (Box 168)
      - Time-Life Books edit conference, Hot Springs, Va., 12-14 Nov. (Box 168)
      - United Nations ambassadors visit, New York, N.Y., 11 Mar. (Box 168)
      - Video weekly magazine (Box 168)
      - World Press Freedom Committee (Box 168)
    - 1981
      - Adler, Mortimer, J., Paideia project (Box 168)
      - "American Renewal/Revival", (2 folders) (Box 168)
      - "American Renewal/Revival", (8 folders) (Box 169)
      - Bonfante, Jordan (Box 169)
      - Calderone, Mary S. (Box 169)
      - Council on Foreign Relations Commission on United States Policy Toward the Soviet Union (Box 169)
      - Goodrich, Henry C. (Box 169)
      - Iona College commencement speech, New Rochelle, N.Y., 7 June (Box 170)
      - Jury duty (Box 170)
      - Kiechel, Walter, television programming suggestions (Box 170)
      - Magazine group committee meeting, 24 June (Box 170)
      - Magazine staff meetings, (2 folders) (Box 170)
      - Media and Society Seminars, Columbia University Graduate School of Journalism, New York, N.Y. (Box 170)
      - People and circulation staff meeting, 16 Sept. (Box 170)
      - Reagan, Ronald, dinner, 6 Jan. (Box 170)
      - Sole, Donald B., South African ambassador (Box 170)
      - Speech to Canada's Business Council on national interests, Montreal, Canada, 14 Apr. (Box 170)
      - Staff parties, June (Box 170)
      - Think tanks (Box 170)
      - Time, inc. dinner, Denver, Colo., 18 Mar. (Box 170)
      - Time, inc. workshop on DNA, 3-4 May (Box 170)
      - Time magazine Newstour '81, 16 Oct.-1 Nov. (Box 171)
      - Time-Life Books staff meeting, 10 Aug. (Box 171)
      - United Nations ambassadors visit, New York, N.Y., 29 Apr. (Box 171)
      - Voices of Freedom: A World Conference of Independent News Media, Talloires, France, 15-17 May (Box 171)
      - Washington Star closing, 7 Aug. (Box 171)
      - Western Region of the American Association of Advertising Agencies Convention, Sun Valley, Idaho, 30 Sept.-4 Oct. (Box 171)
    - 1982
      - American Association of Advertising Agencies, editorial panel (Box 172)
      - Association of National Advertisers annual conference, Palm Beach, Fla., 8 Nov. (Box 172)
      - Barnet, Bruce, and Donald Holt, "European Business Publishing" (Box 172)
      - Chicago Council on Foreign Relations (Box 172)
      - Council on Foreign Relations, discussion group on North Africa (Box 172)
      - Council on Foreign Relations, George Ball introduction (Box 172)
      - Discover magazine report, Mitchell and Company, (2 folders) (Box 172)
      - Discover magazine sales meeting, Troutbeck, N.Y., 19 Oct. (Box 172)
      - Foote, Timothy, retirement party, 28 Sept. (Box 172)
      - Foreign Policy Association address, New York, N.Y., 13 Oct. (Box 172)
      - Fortune international proposal (Box 172)
      - Fortune, Walter Bernard redesign (Box 172)
      - Graves, Eleanor (Box 172)
      - Grunwald, Henry A., sixtieth birthday party, 3 Dec. (Box 172)
      - Housing Industry Presidents' Conference, Williamsburg, Va., 23-25 Mar. (Box 172)
      - Hughes, Robert and Victoria (Box 172)
      - Juan Carlos I, King of Spain, 1938- (Box 172)
      - Kosinski, Jerzy (Box 172)
      - Lambsdorff, Otto, Foreign Policy Association (Box 172)
      - Legal (Box 172)
      - Managing editors and executive editors lunch, 14 Dec. (Box 173)
      - Minority recruiting (Box 173)
      - Morton, John, Washington Post Weekly (Box 173)
      - Narjes, Karl-Heinz, Foreign Policy Association (Box 173)
      - Nozick, Robert (Box 173)
      - Quality magazine (Box 173)
      - Quality magazine study of potential readers (Box 173)
      - Raimund von Hofmannsthal Silver Rose presentation, 15 Sept. (Box 173)
      - Remarks to Chicago staff, 9 Feb. (Box 173)
      - Rosen, Clare Mead, farewell lunch, 15 June (Box 173)
      - Santa Fe, N.M., trip, July-Aug., (3 folders) (Box 173)
      - Science magazine reader and potential reader research study, Mitchell and Company (Box 173)
      - Shepley, James R., retirement party, 15 Sept. (Box 174)
      - Society of the Silurians, Inc., news achievement award dinner, 15 Nov. (Box 174)
      - Time, inc. board of directors' pre-meeting dinner, 16 June (Box 174)
      - Time, inc. electronic publishing briefing, 10 June (Box 174)
      - Time, inc. Public Affairs Conference, Captiva Island, Fla., 22 Mar (Box 174)
      - Time, inc. Western Symposium, Santa Barbara, Calif., 28 Feb.-3 Mar., (3 folders) (Box 174)
      - Time-Life Books, (4 folders) (Box 174)
      - Time-Life Books, (2 folders) (Box 175)
      - Together magazine, (2 folders) (Box 175)
      - Volunteer: the National Center for Citizen Involvement, national conference, Yale University, New Haven, Conn., 7 June (Box 175)
      - Weaver, Paul, business lobby department (Box 175)
      - Weinberger, Caspar, Foreign Policy Association (Box 175)
    - 1983
      - American Society of Managing Editors speech, New York, N.Y., 9 Dec. (Box 175)
      - Andropov, Yuri V. (Box 175)
      - Authority (Box 175)
      - Bennett College commencement address, Greensboro, N.C., 8 May (Box 175)
      - Committee for the Free World conference, New York, N.Y., 12-13 Feb. (Box 175)
      - Communication essay for 1982 annual report (Box 175)
      - Council on Foreign Relations, study group on the Soviet Union and the Reagan administration (Box 175)
      - Food Marketing Institute, Time, inc. editors' panel, Washington, D.C., 18 Oct. (Box 175)
      - Granger, Haidee, "First Ladies - A Personal View," television program (Box 175)
      - Graves, Ralph, dinner, 4 Dec. (Box 175)
      - Guzzardi, Walter, Princeton University seminar, 30 Nov. (Box 175)
      - Life sales meeting, Cancun, Mexico, 20 Mar. (Box 176)
      - Los Angeles, Calif., trip, 18-19 Nov. (Box 176)
      - Magazine development (Box 176)
      - Mitterand, Francois, interview (Box 176)
      - Newsweek, fiftieth anniversary address, New York, N.Y., 7 Feb. (Box 176)
      - Quality magazine (Box 176)
      - Rogosin Institute for Medical Research, New York, N.Y. (Box 176)
      - Scientists' Institute for Public Information (Box 176)
      - Shultz, George, (2 folders) (Box 176)
      - Thatcher, Margaret, interview (Box 176)
      - Thomas, Lewis, Time, inc. and the Scientists' Institute for Public Information birthday dinner, 7 Dec. (Box 176)
      - Time, inc. panel discussion, Foreign Policy Association, 22 Mar. (Box 176)
      - Time, inc. staff information (Box 176)
      - Time magazine advertising sales department lunch, Boston, Mass., 16 Dec. (Box 176)
      - Time magazine cover show, Paris, France, 18 Jan. (Box 176)
      - Time magazine Japan issue, 1 Aug. (Box 176)
      - Time magazine sixtieth anniversary, (2 folders) (Box 176)
      - TV-Cable Week, (2 folders) (Box 176)
    - 1984
      - American-Austrian Foundation (Box 176)
      - Bohemian Grove, Monte Rio, Calif. (Box 177)
      - Centrism (Box 177)
      - Chet Huntley Memorial Lecture, New York University, New York, N.Y., 15 Nov., (2 folders) (Box 177)
      - Corporate circulation strategic planning conference, Martha's Vineyard, Mass., 1-5 Oct. (Box 177)
      - Council on Foreign Relations, Armand Hammer introduction, 8 Mar. (Box 177)
      - Council on Foreign Relations, Georgy Arbatov introduction, 7 May (Box 177)
      - Democratic National Convention, San Francisco, Calif. (Box 177)
      - Discover editorial conference, Troutbeck, N.Y., 1-3 Apr. (Box 177)
      - Discover, report on repositioning (Box 177)
      - Discover white paper (Box 177)
      - Employee opinion survey (Box 177)
      - Europe trip, 23 Nov.-5 Dec. (Box 177)
      - Forbes, Malcolm, cruise, 4 July (Box 177)
      - Gorbachev, Mikhail Sergeevich, interview (Box 177)
      - Graves, Ralph, retirement party, 11 Jan. (Box 177)
      - Grunwald, Henry, "Foreign Policy Under Reagan II," Foreign Affairs, no. 63201 (Winter 1984): 219-239 (Box 177)
      - Haig, Alexander Meigs, dinner, 16 Apr. (Box 177)
      - Hammer, Armand, lunch, 1 Mar. (Box 177)
      - Home Office magazine (Box 177)
      - Investment Week, (2 folders) (Box 178)
      - Leisure magazine, (2 folders) (Box 178)
      - Letters to Republican and Democratic delegates (Box 178)
      - Libel (Box 178)
      - Magazine development, (2 folders) (Box 178)
      - Managing editors lunch, 13 Dec. (Box 178)
      - McManus, Jason, retirement (Box 178)
      - Middle East trip, 17-28 Mar. (Box 178)
      - Money business conference, Jamaica, 4 Apr. (Box 178)
      - Non-executive briefing, 6 Dec. (Box 178)
      - Overtime at the New York Times (Box 178)
      - People tenth anniversary (Box 178)
      - Possible Dreams Auction, Martha's Vineyard, Mass., 1984-1987 (Box 178)
      - Power and politics seminar, Martha's Vineyard, Mass., 28 July (Box 178)
      - Quality magazine (Box 178)
      - Quality magazine essay for 1983 annual report (Box 178)
      - Republic of Korea, Ministry of Commerce and Industry dinner, 2 Mar. (Box 178)
      - Republican National Convention, Dallas, Tex. (Box 178)
      - Rohatyn, Felix (Box 178)
      - Sakharov, Andrei (Box 178)
      - Scientists' Institute for Public Information, (2 folders) (Box 178)
      - Speech to advertising women of New York, New York, N.Y., 18 Sept. (Box 178)
      - Steinem, Gloria, birthday dinner, 23 May (Box 178)
      - Study of corporate identity and reputation, Yankelovich, Skelly and White, Inc. (Box 178)
      - Temple-Inland board meeting, 3 May (Box 179)
      - Time, inc. Distinguished Speakers Program (Box 179)
      - Time, inc. management meeting, Long Island, N.Y., 9-10 Oct. (Box 179)
      - Time, inc. management meeting, Troutbeck, N.Y., 12 Jan. (Box 179)
      - Twentieth Century Fund speech, 8 Dec. (Box 179)
      - United States-Soviet Union symposium, Vienna, Austria, 17-18 Nov. (cancelled) (Box 179)
      - Weymouth, Lally (Box 179)
      - Wharton, Clifton, lunch, 9 Mar. (Box 179)
      - White, Theodore H., Making of the President series (Box 179)
      - Woman Weekly magazine (Box 179)
      - Yzaguirre, Raul, president, National Council of La Raza (Box 179)
      - Zhao, Ziyang, Premier of the State Council of the People's Republic of China (Box 179)
    - 1985
      - American Association of Advertising Agencies, annual meeting, White Sulphur Springs, W.V., 15-18 May (Box 179)
      - American-Austrian Foundation (Box 179)
      - American Council on Germany biennial conference, Dallas, Tex., 28-31 Mar. (Box 179)
      - Annual report, 1984 (Box 179)
      - Asiaweek magazine (Box 179)
      - Brine, Ruth, fortieth anniversary lunch, 16 July (Box 179)
      - Case Western University commencement address, Cleveland, Ohio, 22 May (Box 179)
      - Cave, Ray, and Jason McManus retirement party, 9 Dec. (Box 179)
      - Council on Foreign Relations, advisory committee on the council's national role (Box 179)
      - Council on Foreign Relations, fundraising campaign (Box 179)
      - Council on Foreign Relations, study group on television news and American foreign policy (Box 180)
      - Discover magazine, (2 folders) (Box 180)
      - Foreign Policy Association, bi-partisan foreign policy panel (Box 180)
      - Foreign Policy Association, speech on Mikhail Gorbachev interview, 11 Oct. (Box 180)
      - George T. Delacorte Center for Magazine Journalism, Columbia University, New York, N.Y., inaugural address, 20 Mar. (Box 180)
      - Gorbachev, Mikhail Sergeevich, interview (Box 180)
      - HBO reviews (Box 180)
      - "Hollywood: Legend and Reality," traveling exhibit (Box 180)
      - Immigration essay, (2 folders) (Box 180)
      - Legal (Box 180)
      - Leisure magazine (Box 180)
      - London, United Kingdom, trip, 20-29 Apr., (2 folders) (Box 180)
      - Luce, Clare Boothe, dinner, Washington, D.C., 30 May (Box 180)
      - Magazine development (Box 180)
      - Managing editors lunch, 12 Dec. (Box 181)
      - Picture Week magazine (Box 181)
      - Presidential inauguration, 19-22 Jan. (Box 181)
      - Press (Box 181)
      - Public Information, Government and the Media: Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, 9 Feb. (Box 181)
      - Quality magazine, (2 folders) (Box 181)
      - Scientists' Institute for Public Information (Box 181)
      - Sharon v. Time, correspondence and reactions, (2 folders) (Box 181)
      - Skunkworks (Box 181)
      - Southern Living annual editorial conference, Sandestin, Fla., 19-23 May (Box 181)
      - Speech for CM & D group (Box 181)
      - Speech for Sports Illustrated staff, 3 Oct. (Box 181)
      - Time, inc. board of directors' pre-meeting dinner, 17 Apr. (Box 181)
      - Time, inc. board of directors presentation on the editorial process, 18 July (Box 181)
      - Time, inc. Distinguished Speakers Program (Box 181)
      - Time, inc. Executive Dialogue 1985, New Providence, Bahamas, 6-9 May (Box 182)
      - Time, inc. management meeting, Long Island, N.Y., 19-21 Nov. (Box 182)
      - Time, inc. Public Affairs Conference II, Ponte Vedra, Fla., 3-6 Mar. (Box 182)
      - Time/Canada: Update on America '85, Washington D.C., 24-27 Feb., (2 folders) (Box 182)
      - Time magazine Hollywood cover exhibit, Los Angeles, Calif. (Box 182)
      - Time magazine Newstour '85, Pacific Rim, 18-27 Oct., (4 folders) (Box 182)
      - Time magazine sales meeting, Phoenix, Ariz., 31 Mar.-4 Apr. (Box 182)
      - Time-Life Alumni Society (Box 182)
      - Total Health magazine (Box 182)
      - World Press Freedom Committee (Box 182)
    - 1986
      - Adler, Renata, Sharon v. Time, magazine article (Box 183)
      - American-Austrian Foundation (Box 183)
      - Center for Communication, speech honoring Punch Sulzberger, 15 Apr. (Box 183)
      - Council on Foreign Relations, Arthur Burns introduction, 6 Feb. (Box 183)
      - Council on Foreign Relations, study group on the Soviet Union and the Reagan administration (Box 183)
      - Curricula and textbooks (Box 183)
      - Domestic bureau chiefs' meeting, Chicago, Ill., 20-21 Apr. (Box 183)
      - Editorial staff dinner, 29 Apr. (Box 183)
      - Editorial staff dinner, 1 May (Box 183)
      - Editorial staff lunch, 19 Dec. (Box 183)
      - Editors' meeting, 2 Dec. (Box 183)
      - European and middle eastern bureau chiefs meeting, Paris, France, 9-17 May (Box 183)
      - Grunwald, Henry, essay on democracy (Box 183)
      - Grunwald, Henry, journal, (3 folders) (Box 183)
      - "Hollywood: Legend and Reality," traveling exhibit, Washington, D.C., Apr.-May (Box 183)
      - International Center of Photography twelfth anniversary gala, 12 Nov. (Box 183)
      - Legal (Box 183)
      - Leisure magazine (Box 183)
      - Letter to outside directors (Box 184)
      - Life fiftieth anniversary (Box 184)
      - Life futures meeting, Norwich, Conn., 17-18 June (Box 184)
      - Magazine development (Box 184)
      - Newspaper Guild at Time, inc. wage negotiations (Box 184)
      - Parenting magazine (Box 184)
      - Picture Week magazine, (2 folders) (Box 184)
      - Pumpkin Papers Irregulars (Box 184)
      - Quality magazine, (2 folders) (Box 184)
      - Rethinking the newsmagazine (Box 184)
      - Role of the editor in chief (Box 184)
      - Rukeyser, William S., dinner, 17 June (Box 184)
      - Sales development program (Box 184)
      - Scientists' Institute for Public Information (Box 185)
      - Senior editors' dinner, 11 Dec. (Box 185)
      - South Africa newstour (Box 185)
      - Strategic Defense Initiative Conference, Washington, D.C., 3 June (Box 185)
      - Time, inc. board of editors, (3 folders) (Box 185)
      - Time, inc. Distinguished Speakers Program (Box 185)
      - Time, inc. History Vol. III, 1980-1986, (2 folders) (Box 185)
      - Time magazine Australia (Box 185)
      - Time-Life Books twenty-fifth anniversary, 23 June (Box 185)
      - Time-Life International, London, fiftieth anniversary (Box 185)
    - 1987
      - Adler, Mortimer J., "America's Testament," television program on the constitution (Box 185)
      - Annual report, 1986 (Box 185)
      - Articles about Henry Grunwald, (2 folders) (Box 186)
      - Bicentennial of the constitution, (2 folders) (Box 186)
      - Center for Communication, annual award lunch, 27 May (Box 186)
      - Council on Foreign Relations, discussion group on national objectives and priorities in American foreign policy (Box 186)
      - Council on Foreign Relations, study group on Korea (Box 186)
      - Council on Foreign Relations, William E. Colby and Admiral Stansfield Turner introduction, 25 Mar. (Box 186)
      - Discover magazine sale (Box 186)
      - Editorial guildelines manual (Box 186)
      - Epoca magazine interview (Box 186)
      - Ford, Flicky, Time, inc. journalism film project (Box 186)
      - Korea and China trip, 25 May-8 June, (2 folders) (Box 186)
      - Law, libel, and privacy (Box 186)
      - Legal (Box 187)
      - Lunch time forums series (Box 187)
      - Magazine issues Q & A (Box 187)
      - McManus, Jason, appointment as editor in chief (Box 187)
      - Moscow, Russia, trip, 3-10 May, (2 folders) (Box 187)
      - New executive position, Time, inc. (Box 187)
      - New York City Opera Guild (Box 187)
      - Quality magazine (Box 187)
      - Russia research (Box 187)
      - Soviet journalists' dinner, 23 Feb. (Box 187)
      - "Terrorism in a Technological World," international conference and exhibition sponsored by Discover magazine, Washington, D.C., 20-22 Jan. (Box 187)
      - Time magazine Newstour history (Box 187)
      - Time magazine 1987 Newstour to the Soviet Union (Box 187)
      - United States-Japan trade relations roundtable, Fortune and Time editors (Box 187)
      - United States Senate Committee on Foreign Relations, nomination hearing for Henry A. Grunwald to be Ambassador to the Republic of Austria, 9 Dec. (Box 187)
      - World Press Freedom Committee, world conference on censorship, London, United Kingdom, 16-18 Jan. (Box 187)
  - Miscellany, 1941-2005 (Box 188-196)
    Calendars, clippings, notes, and speech material.
    Arranged alphabetically by type of material.
    - Calendars, 1941-1981, (5 folders) (Box 188)
    - Calendars, 1982-1992, (4 folders) (Box 189)
    - Calendars, 1992-1996, (5 folders) (Box 190)
    - Calendars, 1997-1999, (5 folders) (Box 191)
    - Calendars, 2000-2002, (6 folders) (Box 192)
    - Calendars, 2003-2005, (5 folders) (Box 193)
    - Calendars, 1976-1981, (3 folders) (Box 194)
    - Calendars, 1982-1986, (4 folders) (Box 195)
    - Clippings, 1980-1981 (Box 196)
    - Essays, memoranda, and notes, 1944-1987 (Box 196)
    - Salary history, 1982-1993 (Box 196)
    - Speech material, 1971-1987, (2 folders) (Box 196)
- Classified, 1986-1989 (CL 1)
  State Department materials from Grunwald's term as United States ambassador to Austria.
  Arranged according to the series, containers, and folders from which the items were removed.
  - Ambassador Files
    - Bronfman, Edgar, 1989 (Container 90) (CL 1)
    - Communism, 1989 (Container 91) (CL 1)
    - Department of State, 1989 (Container 92) (CL 1)
    - European Chiefs of Mission conference, Brussels, Belgium, 1989 (Container 93) (CL 1)
    - Grunwald, Louise, 1988 (Container 93) (CL 1)
    - Lauder, Ronald, 1986 (Container 93) (CL 1)
    - Memoranda of conversation, 1988-1989 (Container 93) (CL 1)
    - Swearing-in ceremony, 1987 (Container 94) (CL 1)
    - United States Embassy, Vienna, Austria, 1987 (Container 94) (CL 1)
    - Vienna, printed material, 1988 (Container 97) (CL 1)
    - Waldheim, Kurt, 1988 (Container 97) (CL 1)